A Guide to the Mark Kac papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA170
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Reprints, Papers, Lectures, and Correspondence Files, Accession 2006:064, 1934-1986; 9; 11.83 Cubic Feet 9 record storage boxes.
  - Z., Ciesielski, "Some Analytic Aspects of Probabilistic Potential Theory," Zastosowania Matematyki, 1969 (Box 9)
  - "Bose-Einstein Condensation in the Presence in Impurities. II.," J. Math Phys., 15, 183-186, 1974 (Box 9)
  - "A Formula for the Pressure in Statistical Mechanics," by Mark Kac and J.M. Luttinger, 1973 (Box 9)
  - C. J. Thompson, "On the athematical Mechanis, of Phase Transition," Proc. NAS, 55, 676-683, 1966 (Box 9)
  - "Will Computers Replace humans?" (Box 9)
  - "A Mathematician's Look at Physics: What Sets Us Apart and What May Bring Us Together", 1960 (Box 9)
  - "Probability Theory: Its Role and Its Impact," SIAM Review, 4, 1-11, 1962 (Box 9)
  - "Phase Transitions", 1973 (Box 9)
  - "Toward a Unified View on Mathematical Theories in Physics", 1968 (Box 9)
  - "Some Mathematical Problems Suggestd by Questions in Physics", 1981 (Box 9)
  - "An Elementary Queuing Problem," by P. E. Boudreau, J. S. Griffin, Jr., and Mark Kac, 1962 (Box 9)
  - "Scattering Length and Capacity," by Mark Kac and J. M. Luttinger, 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Wiener and Integration in Function Spaces", 1966 (Box 9)
  - "Distribution of Eigenvalues of Certain Integral Operators", 1956 (Box 9)
  - "The Search for the Meaning of Independence," in The Making of Statisticians, Ed. by J. Gani (Box 9)
  - Book Reviews (Box 9)
  - "Some Probabilistic Aspects of the Boltzmann Equation", 1973 (Box 9)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of the Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. II. Discussion o the Distribution Fuctions," by G. E. Uhlenback, P. C. Hemmer, and Mark Kac, 1963 (Box 9)
  - "One Diensional Gas in Gravity," by Mark Kac and Colin J. Thompson, 1969 (Box 9)
  - "Some Reflections of a Mathematician on the Nature and the Role of Statistics", 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Statisatical Mechanics of Assemblies of Coupled Oscillators," by G. W. Ford, Mark Kac, and P. Mazur, 1965 (Box 9)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. I. Discussion of a One-Dimensional Model", 1963 (Box 9)
  - "Critical Behavior of Several Lattice Models with Long-Range Interaction", 1969 (Box 9)
  - "Statistical Mechanics of Some One-Dimensional Systems" (Box 9)
  - "A Discrete Verison of the Inverse Scattering Problem," by K. M. Case and Mark Kac, 1973 (Box 9)
  - "A Formula for the Pressure in Statistical Mechanics", 1973 (Box 9)
  - "Semiclassical Quantum Mechanics and Morse's Theory" (Box 9)
  - "Nonlinear Dynamics and Inverse Problems" (Box 9)
  - "On Occupation Times for Markoff Processes," by D. A. Darling and Mark Kac, 1957 (Box 9)
  - "Some Probabilistic Aspects of Scattering Theory" (Box 9)
  - "A Class of Limit Theorems", 1957 (Box 9)
  - "A Mathematician Looks at Medicine", 1979 (Box 9)
  - "Study of Several Lattice Systems with Long-Range Forces", 1963 (Box 9)
  - Bibliography (Box 9)
  - "Will Computers Replace Humans" in The Greatest Adventure: Basic Research That Shapes Our Lives, 1974 (Box 9)
  - "Stochastic Processes and Their Application to the Theory of Cosmic Radiation," Physics Today, Review, 1950 January (Box 9)
  - Book Review, Physics Today, 1957 February (Box 9)
  - "Bose-Einstein Condensation in the Presence of Impurities", 1973 (Box 9)
  - "On Certain Toeplitz-like Matrices and Their Relation to the Problem of Lattice Vibrarions," Nordita Publications, 1968 (Box 9)
  - "Some Combinatorial Aspects of the Theory of Toeplitz Matrices", 1964 (Box 9)
  - "Some Annalistic Aspects of Probabilstic Potential Theory," by Z. Ciesielski and Mark Kac, 1969 (Box 9)
  - "Critical Behavior of Several Lattice Models with Long-Range Interaction", 1969 (Box 9)
  - "Some Mathematical Models in Science", 1969 (Box 9)
  - "One Dimensional Gas in Gravity", 1969 (Box 9)
  - Physics Today, Vol, 17, No. 10, 1964 October (Box 9)
  - Liberal Education: Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association of American Colleges, 1966 March (Box 9)
  - "Phase Transition and Eigenvalue Degeneracy oof a One-Dimensional Anaharmonic Oscillator," by Colin J. Thompsson and Mark Kac (Box 9)
  - "Study of Several Lattice Systems with Long-Range Forces", 1963 (Box 9)
  - "Statistical Mechanics of Some One-Dimensional Systems" (Box 9)
  - "Matematyka, jej kierunki I napiecia", 1963 (Box 9)
  - "Probability Theory as a Mathematical Discipline and as a Tool in Engineering and Science", 1963 (Box 9)
  - "Matematyka, jej kierunki I napiecia", 1963 (Box 9)
  - "Mark Kac on Mathematics," Boston University Journal, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Josiah Willard Gibbs Lecture, AMerican Mathematical Society, 1967 (Box 9)
  - "Possible Origin of the Quantized Vortices in He II," b y S. J. Outterman, Mark Kac, G. E. Uhlenbeck, 1972 (Box 9)
  - "Some Probabilistic Aspects of the Boltzmann Equation", 1973 (Box 9)
  - "Some Mathematical Prob;ems Suggested by Questions in Physics", 1981 (Box 9)
  - "A Note on Learning Signal Detection", 1962 (Box 9)
  - "Mathematics: Its Trends and Its Tensions," in Occasional Paper of the Rockefeller Institute (Box 9)
  - "Chapter 10: On Some Mathematical Models Exhibiting Phase Transition and on What Might be Learned from Them" (Box 9)
  - Ahu, S., Reprint (Box 9)
  - "Analysis of a Basic Queuing Problem Arising in Computer Systems," by P. E. Boudreau, and Mark Kac, 1961 April (Box 9)
  - "The Three Body Toda System and a Parameterization of Plane Cubic Curves" (Box 9)
  - "Fluctuations and the Boltzmann Equation. I." by Jonathan Logan and Mark Kac, 1976 (Box 9)
  - "On Some Modified Spherical Models," by Wayne W. Barrett and Mark Kac, 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Note on the Distribution of Values of the Arithmetic Function d(m)1," in the Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, 1941 (Box 9)
  - "Fluctuations Near and Far from Equilibrium", 1977 (Box 9)
  - "Methodes Probabilistes dans la Theorie du Potentiel", 1956 (Box 9)
  - "An Elementary Queuing Problem," by P. E. Boudreau, J. S. Griffin, Jr., and Mark Kac, 1962 (Box 9)
  - "A Discrete Queuing Problem with Variable Service Times," by P. E. Boudreau, J. S. Griffin, Jr., and Mark Kac, 1962 (Box 9)
  - "On the Partition Function of a One-Dimensional Gas", 1959 (Box 9)
  - "Semiclassical Quantum Mechanics and Morse's Theory" (Box 9)
  - "Probability" (Box 9)
  - "On an Explicitly Soluble System of Nonlinear DIfferential Equations Related to Certain Toda Lattices", 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Toward a Unified View on Mathematical Theories of Phase Transitions", 1968 (Box 9)
  - "On the Asymptotic Number of Bound States for Certain Attractive Potentials", 1978 (Box 9)
  - "Spherical Model and the Infinite Spin Dimensionality Limit" (Box 9)
  - "Some Probabilistic Aspects of Scattering Theory," in Functional Intgration and Its Applications: Proceedings of the International Conference Held at Cumberland Lodge, Wndsor Great Park, London, 1974 April, 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Fluctuations Near and Far from Equilibrium", 1977 (Box 9)
  - "Toward a Unified View on Mathematical Theories of Phase Transitions", 1968 (Box 9)
  - "A Discrete Version of the Inverse Scattering Problem," by K. M. Case and Mark Kac, 1973 (Box 9)
  - "A Complete Solution of the Periodic Toda Problem", 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Propagation of Chaos and the Burgers Equation," by E. Gutkin and Mark Kac, 1983 (Box 9)
  - "A Note on Learning Signal Detection", 1962 (Box 9)
  - "Correlation Functions in the Spherical and Mean Spherical Models", 1977 (Box 9)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of the Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. II. Discussion of the Distribution Functions," G. E. Uhlenbeck, P. C. Hemmer, and Mark Kac, 1963 (Box 9)
  - "Study of Several Lattice Systems with Long-Range Forces", 1963 (Box 9)
  - "On the van der Waals Theory of the Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium. I. Discussion of a One-Dimensional Model," "Stochastic Differential Equations. VII: The Physical Background of Langevin's Equation," in Lecture Series in Differential Equations, 1963 (Box 9)
  - "Lectures on Mathematical Aspects of Phase Transitions," in Studies in Mathematical Physics, 1970 (Box 9)
  - "Phase Transitions", 1973 (Box 9)
  - "The Work of T. H. Berlin in Statistical Mechanics...a Personal Reminiscence", 1964 (Box 9)
  - "On the Quantum Langevin Equation," by Rafael Benguria and Mark Kac (Box 9)
  - "Some Probabilitic Aspects of Scattering Theory" (Box 9)
  - "Probability Theory: Its Role and Its Impact", 1962 (Box 9)
  - "Toward a Unified View on Mathematical Theories of Phase Transitions", 1968 (Box 9)
  - "Statistical Mechanics of Some One-Demenisional Systems", 1962 (Box 9)
  - "A Remark on Wiener's Tauberian Theorem", 1962 (Box 9)
  - "On the Mathematical Mechanism of Phase Transition", 1966 (Box 9)
  - "A Mathematician Looks at Medicine", 1979 (Box 9)
  - "Mathematial Mechanisms of Phase Transitions", 1967 (Box 9)
  - "The Social Responsibility of the Academic Community," in the Journal of the Franklin Institute: Special Issue, 1975 (Box 9)
  - "A Mathematical View of the Theory of Phase Changes," in Perspectives in Modern Physics, 1966 (Box 9)
  - "A Mathematician's Look at Physics: Wheat Sets Us Apart and What May Bring Us Together," An Address Delivered at the Opeining Session of the Second Semiar on Applied Mathematics, 1960 July 23 (Box 9)
  - "Probability," in Scientific American, 1964 (Box 9)
  - "Probability" in The Mathematical Sciences (Box 9)
  - "Memoir of a Physicist," Review of Why I Left Canada by Leopold Infeld, 1979 (Box 9)
  - "The Phyiscal Background of Langevin's Equation" (Box 9)
  - "Some Probabilistic Aspects of Scattering Theory" (Box 9)
  - "Some Remarks on Stable Processes" (Box 9)
  - Review by Kenneth O. May of Mathematics and Logic. Retrospect and Prospect by Mark Kac ad Stanislaw Ulam, 1969 (Box 9)
  - "Probability Theory: Its Role and Its Impact", 1962 (Box 9)
  - Program for Cornell University Centennial Symposia, The Great Problems: A Program for Investigation, 1965 (Box 9)
  - "Study of Several Lattice Systems with Long-Range Forces", 1963 (Box 9)
  - "Quantum Langevin Equation," by Rafael Benguria and Mark Kac, 1981 (Box 9)
  - "A Formula for the Pressure in Statistical Mechanics", 1973 (Box 9)
  - "Bose-Einstein Condensation in the Presence of Impurities. II.", 1974 (Box 9)